Now, how to search a 2D array for a specific element in order to search through the array for a specific
element.
We start by making a like, for example, a method called search 2D array and it looks for it and called
value.
OK.
And since we are dealing with 2D array, we need a nested loop.
So the first nested loop, the outer loop, it creates an integer row equal to zero, the growth rate,
the length.
So and we are going to pass through all the elements since we are dealing with row + plus.
OK.
This is the rule.
This is that whole loop that loops it through or iterate through all the rows of that to the array.
Now we have a second loop for loop that creates an integer call this four column and passed through
all the columns because column call plus plus there reached array at index zero that length array of
index zero.
This indicates the rows I'm making.
I'm looping through all the rows, so rows total length.
If we have five rows, it will indicate five rows.
OK.
This is how we search for a specific element and by implementing and creating it to 2D or nested loops,
OK?
And to search for it to the array inside to the.
OK if!
Array F Row index through in this column.
Equal equal to the value that we are going to search for, then system that the brand, the value found
at, at specific and this specific call and return.
Otherwise the value is not found.
This is how we search for it to the attorney.
I hope you write this down because you may ask it in the university exams or in the interview to write
an algorithm that searches for to the array for specificamente.
OK.
So these are the codes for searching to the app.
Now let's see the complexity time complexity for the first element for the first loop will create in
all of us because we are searching for Arrow.
Let all the rows.
If we have five arrows, then we are going to search for five elements five iterations.
The second one is all C because we if we have five columns, then we have to iterate through all the
five rows and five columns.
OK.
So if I equal to five and see equal to five, then we need to make five iterations because five four
rows and five every zero.
OK.
This indication is if all of one, because I'm just comparing the value system to Sprint as of right
now, the nested loops were resolved in time complexity of all our time.
See their old times columns.
OK, and we have seen this in that big own rotation when searching to the array.
And we have seen that if we have a matrix like in the same row and the same column, then it is off
and square or our square or C square.
If you want the then dynamic collation and name collation is not, there is not a big deal.
But we need to understand why we are putting our library, not putting see and why we are multiplying
the.